Mss.Ms.Coll.200
American Philosophical Society
- Papers
  - Letter to --, Undated; Unidentified
    L. 2p. Draft. Concerning a letter from [Alexander?] Patterson concerning the Wyoming valley controversy. Presented by Arthur Bloch, Dec. 3, 1952.
  - Letter to --, Undated; Unidentified
    L. 3p. Concerning possible law for harbor pilots.
  - Letter to Anna Bartram, Undated; Unidentified
    Xerox of L. 1p. and add. Invites her to visit and stay the night.
  - Letter to [J.F.?] Gronovius, Undated; Unidentified
    Photo. of A.L.S. 1p. and add.
  - Letter to James Burd(?), Undated; Unidentified
    1p. Fragment.
  - List of books and prices, Undated; Unidentified
    D. 37p. Mentions B. Franklin.
  - List of works by Auguste Carlier, Undated; Unidentified
  - Listing of contents of a house., Undated; Unidentified
    D. 12p. In French. Presented by J. Bennett Nolan.
  - Memoir of Robert Morris, Undated; Unidentified
    D. 6p.
  - Memorandum. List of eight documents from 1681 to 1966., Undated; Unidentified
  - Memorandum from old papers relative to Pennepacker Mills., Undated; Unidentified
    D. 2p. Presented by Elizabeth Cadwallader Wood, Dec., 1975.
  - Memorandum of persons living to great ages., Undated; Unidentified
  - Method of putting up wire fences, Undated; Unidentified
  - Notes on electricity, taken from publications, including Franklin's., Undated; Unidentified
    D. 3p. This was removed, May 1962, from 537:F851e.
  - Note on James Otis, Undated; Unidentified
    A.D. 2p. Found in Wm. Tudor's Life of James Otis. Note on Tudor's Life. Mentions Adams and Franklin.
  - Notes to Baron de Hupsch von Lontzen, pertaining to the curing and preservation of animal and bird skins..., Undated; Unidentified
    D. 6p. In English and French. [Removed from a pamphlet by Hupsch von Lontzen (Pam.1195, no. 2) by Spawn, June 1965.]
  - Note to "Dear C", Undated; Unidentified
    A.N. 1p. Concerns Darwin letters and study of the hedgehog by Huxley, Darwin and Ball.
  - Observations on the phenomena of the lever., Undated; Unidentified
    D. 24p.
  - On the logic of geometry, Undated; Unidentified
    D. 19p.
  - On vapor, or the generation of steam., Undated; Unidentified
  - Preliminary report on the Tench Coxe papers., Undated; Unidentified
    Typed D. viii, 36 leaves. The Tench Coxe papers are not in the possession of the APS.
  - Recipes for making grape wine and spiced rhubarb., Undated; Unidentified
    D. 2 pieces.
  - Survey of the house and observatory of David Rittenhouse, Undated; Unidentified
    Photo. of D. 2p. Presented by John Daly, June, 1973.
  - Ticket, signed by G. Cuvier, Undated; Unidentified
    Jardin du Roi ticket.
  - Turkish document, signed for the sultan., Undated; Unidentified
    D. 2p., end. by John Vaughan. Preented by John P. Brown, Feb. 19, 1836.
  - "The Key to the American Riddle [according to the interpretation of the book of Revelations].", Undated; 13-1/2x8-1/2; Unidentified
    Bible. New Testament. Revelations. D. 5p.
  - Letter to Gen. [William] North, Undated; 9 1/2" x 7 3/4"; Vaughan, Benjamin, 1751-1835
    Sept. 26. Hallowell, A.L.S. 1p. Congratulations on his son's marriage to Miss Bridge.
  - Memorandum., Undated; 5x8; Vaughan, John, 1756-1841
    A.D. 1p. Concerning the right of the society to answer a request. On same sheet as letter from Joseph Sansom to Robert Patterson; Monday morning [1790?].
  - Journal., Undated; Vigny, Alfred de, 1797-1863
    Photo. 1p. From original in Collection Lovenjoul, Chantilly, France. Presented by Irving Massey, grantee, 1966.
  - Letter to Mc H, Undated; W., J. F.
    Dec. 10. A.L.S. 2p., enc. wanting. Sends pictures of Philadelphia. Mentions [John?] Vaughan. Located in Library; July 26, 1974.
  - Letter to "Dear Sir;", Undated; 5x3-1/2; Warden, David Bailie, 1772-1845
    Wednesday. A.L.S. 1p. Forwards ticket for the meeting of the agricultural society.
  - Letter to Mr. Todd, Paris, Undated; 8x5; Warden, David Bailie, 1772-1845
    Aug. 5. A.L.S. 2p.and add. Le Ray de Chaumont said he was leaving Paris soon, and Warden wants him to take some letters to the U.S. for him.
  - Letter to [James] Brant Bey, Undated; Washington, Horace Lea
    Wednesday. A.L.S. 1p. Thanks for translating the seal.
  - Inventory of manuscripts preserved at Doldowlod, Radnorshire., Undated; Watt, James, 1736-1819
    Xerox of typed D. 37p.
  - The Secretary of the Continental Congress: Charles Thomson, Undated; White, Cyril
    T.D. 7p.
  - Manuscript note on the church in America., Undated; 11x7-1/2; White, William, 1748-1836
    Photo-Lithograph of A.D. 4p.and engraving of White, bound in paper covers; 1877. Presented by James Bennett Nolan; May 3, 1956.
  - Convocation address: University of Alberta, Undated; Wigner, Eugene Paul, 1902-1995
    Typed D.S. 4p.
  - Letter to Dr. [Thomas Darlington] Cope, Undated; Will, Homer
    A.L.S. 1p. Found in: 506.73/P38n. Sending Pa. Acdemy of Science Newsletter.
  - Letter to [Elbridge] Gerry, Undated; 6" x 7 1/2"; Winthrop, James
    Thursday noon. A.L. in 3d P. 2p. Gives his opinion relative to preferred type of electrical rods; mentions Dr. Franklin. FILM54-61 FRAME225
  - A pseudo-Platonic dialogue..., Undated; 11x8-1/2; Wright, John Kirtland, 1891-1969
    Typed D. 13p. Concerning a biography of him to be written. Presented by the author; April 14, 1966.
  - John Meem., Undated; 11x8-1/2; Young, Henry J.
    Typed D. 4p. Presented by the Historical society of York County, Feb. 15, 1947.
  - Letter to "Dear Sir", Undated; Younghusband, Edward Francis, Sir, 1863-1942
    Oct. 11. A.L.S. 2p. Setting up and appointment to meet. Concern with leases on two Indian forests.
  - Letter to Tiberius Cavallo, London, Undated; Zach, Franz Xaver, Freiherr von, 1754-1832
    A.L. 4p., add. Concerning astronomical observations, and gives readings. Refers to Royal Society, Sir Joseph Banks, microscope, telescopes, Peter Dollond, Herschel and Masklyne. Praises his publications on air, elastic fluids, chemistry, and reports that Volta was impressed by them.